<lesson>
<header><p>Program Objective</p></header>
<copy><copy><p>Let's go over some of the basic concepts about speed reading and The Reader's Edge to ensure you have the proper objectives in mind.<br /></p></copy></copy><copy><copy><p>In today's information-based society, reading ability is one of our most important skills. It's easy to feel overwhelmed by the amount we have to read when a typical adult's average reading rate is limited to only 160-220 words-per-minute, about the same rate at which we speak. That's too slow for today's demands.<br /></p></copy></copy><copy><copy><p>One of the most important things to remember is that &quot;speed reading&quot; alone is meaningless without simultaneously considering comprehension. The goal of The Reader's Edge is to teach you to unlearn the habits of inefficient readers and learn the habits and skills of efficient readers. Efficient Readers are effective and efficient speed readers, they read better and faster with improved comprehension, retention, and recall. You will be able to apply the new skills you learn with The Reader's Edge to your everyday reading of newspapers, emails, magazines and books, not just while working on the computer. Your newly learned skills will become as permanent as the skill of riding a bike.<br /></p></copy></copy><copy><copy><p>An important step to becoming an Efficient Reader is to understand the difference between Efficient and Inefficient reading skills. When learning to read, we were taught Learn To Read skills, i.e., to read one word at a time, aloud to a teacher or parent.<br /></p></copy></copy><copy><copy><p>After that point, we moved into a world of silent reading, which requires a new set of skills. These new silent reading skills are the opposite of those required for reading one word at a time out loud. Silent reading are the Read To Learn skills that have never been taught in regular reading curriculums. This is where The Reader's Edge comes in. It teaches the silent reading skills necessary for individuals of all ages to become Efficient Readers. Let's look at the important differences between Inefficient Readers and Efficient Readers:<br /></p></copy></copy><copy><copy><p><b>Inefficient Readers</b><br /></p></copy></copy><copy><copy><p><ul><li>See and read one word at a time </li><br /><li>Fixate on each word in a sentence </li><br /><li>Read slowly and laboriously </li><br /><li>Re-read words to gain comprehension </li><br /><li>Vocalize (subliminally or lip) each word as they are read </li><br /><li>Find it difficult to obtain the meaning of unfamiliar words from context, thus reducing comprehension </li><br /><li>Generally believe the myth that one must read slowly to have good comprehension </li><br /><li>Have limited vocabularies</li></ul></p></copy></copy><copy><copy><p>Efficient Readers<br /></p></copy></copy><copy><copy><p><ul><li>See and read groups of words with each eye fixation </li><br /><li>Do not re-read words </li><br /><li>Do not vocalize </li><br /><li>Have higher levels of comprehension because they are reading groups of words, or units of meaning, and can derive meanings of words from context </li><br /><li>Dispel the popular speed reading myth that one must read slowly to have good comprehension </li><br /><li>Have large vocabularies</li></ul></p></copy></copy><copy><copy><p>Once you understand the differences between the two types of readers, the benefits of becoming an Efficient Reader are obvious.<br /></p></copy></copy><copy><copy><p>When ready, move onto the next lesson and start working with the program. </p></copy></copy>
<copy><p><br /></p></copy>
</lesson>
